Mahendra Duwal Shrestha

4831 E Summit Cir Apt 136 ● Knoxville, TN 37919 ● (865) 441-7363 ● <u>mduwalsh@vols.utk.edu</u>

• <u>duwal.mahendra@gmail.com</u>

SUMMARY

A software engineer with 2.5 years of professional industry experience in C#, Asp.Net, Java, Grails. Proven abilities in analysis, test development and application development in both new and existing projects. 2.5 years of research experience in developing mathematical simulation programs involving cluster computations in C/C++.

EDUCATION

MS in Computer Science, The University of Tennessee, Knoxville, GPA: 3.9

2014-2017

Major courses taken: Computer Systems Organization, Software Systems, Algorithms, Introduction to Pattern Recognition, Databases and Scripting Languages, Applied Cryptography, Distributed System Algorithms

Thesis: Efficient Simulation Of A Simple Evolutionary System

BE in Electronics and Communication Engineering, Pulchowk Engineering

2007-2011

Campus, Tribhuvan University, Nepal, GPA: 3.8

SKILLS SUMMARY

Programming Language: C, C++, Java, C#, Python, Groovy, Javascript, PHP, Perl

• Web Technologies: HTML5, Groovy on Grails, ASP.Net, ASP.Net MVC, Ajax, Jquery, JSON,

Spring MVC

• Version Control: git, SVN

• Databases: MYSQL, MSSQL

• Tools: Gnuplot, pthreads, CUDA, OpenMP, Hadoop, MATLAB, R, Visual Studio,

TFS, Eclipse, IntellijIdea, Emacs, Latex

SDLC: Waterfall, Agile ScrumPlatforms: Linux, Windows, Unix

EXPERIENCE

Graduate Teaching / Research Assistant, The University of Tennessee, TN

8/2014 - 2017

- Graded assignments and projects, and tutored for undergraduate classes 'Algorithm Analysis and Automata' and 'Software Engineering' during academic year 2014 - 2015
- Developed programs for agent-based simulations of mathematical models and plotting graphs using C/C++ and gnuplot for Dr. Sergey Gavrilets in Ecology and Evolutionary Biology Department during 2014 – 2017
- Used cluster computing for simulations and fixed maintenance issues in the cluster

Software Engineer, Deerwalk Services Pvt. Ltd., Nepal

1/2012 - 7/2014

- Developed web applications using agile methodology for health care system management in US using ASP.Net, ASP.Net MVC and C# as a member of outsourcing service provider team
- Designed and developed database schema and stored procedures in MSSQL
- Developed and maintained US health care system management web application modules using Grails
 framework as a member of Deerwalk's product's team
- Designed and developed database schema, scripts and stored procedures in MYSQL
- Led developer's team for development and optimization of generic MYSQL scripts for importing staged data from multiple clients into company's product's database system